[
    {
        "question": "Name the season when field visits are being undertaken.",
        "options": [
            "Summer",
            "Monsoon",
            "Winter"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Maharashtra forts were built for ………….. purpose.",
        "options": [
            "Security",
            "Entertainment",
            "Hiding"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "With the help of a Teacher students prepare a …………… before going to the field visit.",
        "options": [
            "Questionnaire",
            "Report",
            "Map"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "One should ensure not to harm the …………… during field visit.",
        "options": [
            "Trees",
            "Animals",
            "Environment"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "………….. is to be carried for any emergency circumstances.",
        "options": [
            "Water-bottle",
            "First aid",
            "Mobile-phone"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "………….. is the source of information during field visit.",
        "options": [
            "BMC office",
            "Local office",
            "District office"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Circle the odd one:",
        "options": [
            "Note-book",
            "Pen",
            "Spectacles",
            "Compass"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "A field report should be written on the basis of the …………… obtained after the field visit.",
        "options": [
            "Pictures",
            "Information",
            "Maps"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Multi-purpose projects provide water for ……………",
        "options": [
            "Agriculture",
            "Animals",
            "Forests"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Geographical concepts and elements can be directly experienced through …………..",
        "options": [
            "Maps",
            "Field visits",
            "Slides"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Mud and wood houses are cheap and …………..",
        "options": [
            "Eco-friendly",
            "Strong",
            "Complicated"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "It is necessary to converse with …………… people to understand their problems.",
        "options": [
            "Village",
            "Local",
            "City"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The ground rule is to obey the …………… of the teachers.",
        "options": [
            "Rules",
            "Instructions",
            "Laws"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Maharashtra plateau is made up of ……………. rocks.",
        "options": [
            "Basalt",
            "Sedimentary",
            "Metamorphic"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Maharashtra plateau is formed due to …………… volcanic eruption.",
        "options": [
            "Fissure",
            "Conical",
            "Active"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Give one word for greenery on the out streets of the village.",
        "options": [
            "Orchard",
            "Garden",
            "Devrai"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Field visit one useful for understanding the correlation between environment and …………..",
        "options": [
            "Climate",
            "Animals",
            "Humans"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "Students carry camera to click selfies during field visit.",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Position of the sun, moon and earth affect the …………….",
        "options": [
            "Waves",
            "Tides",
            "Tsunamis"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Permission letter has to be acquire ……………. going to the field visit.",
        "options": [
            "Before",
            "After",
            "Same day"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    } 
    
]